MILAN WIEDEMANN

Wolfson College, Linton Road, OX2 6UD Oxford milan.wiedemann@gmail.com \diamond www.milanwiedemann.com

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a DPhil student at the University of Oxford investigating processes of change in cognitive therapy for Posttraumatic Stress Disorder. My main research interest is evidence-based health care, particularly in clinical psychology. I believe in the benefits of open science practices and try to implement them in my work as much as possible. I am also enthusiastic about creative work, like filming, video editing, or photography, to communicate research outputs with the wider public.

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

University of Oxford

October 2016 - Present

DPhil in Experimental Psychology

Thesis: Processes of change in cognitive therapy for Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Supervised by Prof. Anke Ehlers and Prof. David M. Clark

Technische Universität Braunschweig

August 2013 - September 2015

MSc in Psychology

Main focus: Clinical Psychology

Technische Universität Braunschweig

August 2011 - September 2013

BSc in Psychology

University of Groningen

September 2010 - August 2011

BSc in Psychology

DRK-Rettungsschule Goslar

January 2011- February 2011

Rettungssanitäter (in english 'Ambulance Care Assistant')

CLINICAL & RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of Oxford

October 2016 - Present

Part-time Research Assistant, Oxford Centre for Anxiety Disorders and Trauma

Oxford, UK

- · Creating videos for training clinical psychologists in specialised cognitive behavioural treatments.
- · Teaching and supervising Research Assistants in filming and editing techniques.

University of Oxford

April 2015 - August 2016

Research Assistant, Oxford Centre for Anxiety Disorders and Trauma

Oxford, UK

- · Filming patient testimonies and videos with clinical psychologists for internet treatments.
- · Creating whiteboard videos and animating psycho-educational illustrations.
- · Uploading text, video and audio content to online therapy programmes.

Technische Universität Braunschweig

September 2012 - March 2015

Part-time Research Assistant, Institute of Clinical Psychology

Braunschweig, GER

- · Conducting clinical interviews with adolescents for a longitudinal study.
- · Analysing quantitative data from a longitudinal study.
- · Managing and setting up large databases for national and international research teams.

Local Health Authority Berlin Pankow

Intern, Social Psychiatric Department

Berlin, GER

- · Conducting clinical interviews with adolescents for a longitudinal study.
- · Analysing quantitative data from a longitudinal study.
- · Managing and setting up large databases for national and international research teams.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Oxford

January 2018 - February 2018

February 2012 - March 2012

Demonstrator, Department of Experimental Psychology

Oxford, UK

· Module: Psychological Disorders and Individual Differences.

Technische Universität Braunschweig

November 2014 - March 2015

Teaching Assistant, Institute of Clinical Psychology

Braunschweig, GER

· Module: Practical Course of Psychological Diagnostics.

Technische Universität Braunschweig

April 2014 - September 2014

Teaching Assistant, Institute of Clinical Psychology

Braunschweig, GER

· Module: Fundamentals of Psychological Diagnostics.

Technische Universität Braunschweig

September 2012 - January 2014

Teaching Assistant, Institute of Methodology and Biopsychology

Braunschweig, GER

· Module: Laboratory Experience and Analysis with Statistical Software.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

University of Oxford

July 2017 - September 2017

Part-time Research Assistant, Faculty of History

Oxford, UK

· Filming and editing of the workshop 'Changing lives: Understanding what enables children growing up in adversity to thrive in modern Britain'.

Arbeiter-Samariter-Bund Braunschweig

May 2010 - March 2015

Ambulance Care Assistant

Braunschweig, GER

- · Medical care during the qualified transport of patients.
- · First aid and emergency treatment of patients.
- · Independent ambulance coach driver in the in-house emergency centre.

Arbeiter-Samariter-Bund Braunschweig

July 2008 - March 2009

Civilian Service

Braunschweig, GER

- · Getting trained as an 'Ambulance Care Assistant'.
- · Medical care during the qualified transport of patients.
- \cdot Independent ambulance coach driver in the in-house emergency centre.

SCHOLARSHIPS

Mental Health Research UK

May 2018

 $Travel\ Grant$

· Networks Summer School 2018 in Amsterdam.

University of Oxford, Wolfson College

June 2017

Travel Grant

· Conference of the European Association for Behavioural and Cognitive Therapies in 2017.

Mental Health Research UK

October 2016

PhD Scholarship

· Full-time PhD scholarship for up to four years.

Erasmus plus

February 2015

Graduate Student Scholarship

· Financial support for an internship at the Oxford Centre for Anxiety Disorders and Trauma.

SELECTION OF PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Advanced structural equation modelling

May 2018

Summer School (5 days), University of Oxford, Department of Education

Testing for Mediation and Moderation using Mplus

June 2017

Workshop (1 day), Figure It Out - Statistical Consultancy and Training

Multilevel analysis for longitudinal data

February 2016

Workshop (3 days), Universität Landau, Methodenzentrum

Structural equation models for longitudinal data

February 2016

Workshop (2 days), Universität Landau, Methodenzentrum

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Statistical analysis & Data science Scientific writing & Office programs Video & Audio editing Driving licence R, GitHub, Mplus, JASP, Jamovi, Praat, SPSS R-Markdown, LATEX, iWork, Microsoft Office Final Cut X, Audacity, iZotope RX Clean category B

PUBLICATIONS & PRESENTATIONS

Peer-reviewed

1] Jennifer Wild, Emma Warnock-Parkes, Nick Grey, Richard Stott, **Milan Wiedemann**, Lauren Canvin, Harriet Rankin, Emma Shepherd, Ava Forkert, David M Clark, and Anke Ehlers. "Internet-delivered cognitive therapy for PTSD: A development pilot series". In: *European Journal of Psychotraumatology* 7.1 (2016). DOI: 10.3402/ejpt.v7.31019.

Software

[1] Milan Wiedemann, Graham R Thew, and Richard Stott. suddengains: An R package to identify sudden gains in psychological therapies. R package version 0.0.0.9001. 2018. URL: https://github.com/milanwiedemann/suddengains.

Selected presentations

- [1] **Milan Wiedemann**, David M Clark, and Anke Ehlers. "Predictors and processes of sudden gains in cognitive therapy for PTSD". In: *European Association for Behavioural and Cognitive Therapies*, *Ljubljana* (2017).
- [2] **Milan Wiedemann**, David M Clark, and Anke Ehlers. "Sudden gains in cognitive therapy for PTSD Can large and stable improvements between sessions help us understand how therapy works?" In: *University of Exeter, Mood Disorder Centre, The Think-Tank Seminar* (2018).